校 园 风 云
翠茜・佛立克竞选学生会主席 （请签名支持)
- Hey, Mr McAllister. - Not wasting any time, are you?
- 麦考利斯特老师 - 你真是把握时间
- You know about the early bird. - Yeah, I do.
- 早起的鸟儿有虫吃 - 没错
- Good luck there, Tracy. - Thanks. I'll see you in class.
- 祝你好运，翠茜 - 谢谢，课堂上见
None of this would have happened if Mr McAllister hadn't meddled.
要不是麦考利斯特老师从中作梗 这一切就不会发生
He should have accepted things and not tried to interfere with destiny.
他应该接受现实 而不是试图干涉命运
You can't interfere with destiny, that's why it's destiny.
人力是无法干涉命运的 所以才叫做命运
If you try to interfere, the same thing's going to happen anyway.
不管你如何介入 同样的事还是会发生
It's hard to remember how it started, the whole election mess.
记不清楚这场选举闹剧 是怎么开始的
I do remember that I loved my job. I was a teacher, an educator.
只记得我深爱我的工作 我是个老师，一位教育者
I couldn't imagine doing anything else.
我无法想像自己还能做些什么
Mr McAllister, quit daydreaming and get back to work.
麦考利斯特老师，别发呆了 好好工作
The students knew it wasn't just a job for me. I got involved.
学生们了解这不只是我的工作 我投入其中
Put down the cards, boys. This game is over.
放下纸牌，各位，游戏结束了
Come on, Wolverines. Defence!
加油，小狼队，防守
I knew I touched their lives during their difficult young-adult years.
在他们的青涩岁月里 我与他们的生活紧紧相系
I took that responsibility seriously.
我认真地看待这份职责
In the 12 years I taught history and current events at Carver-
我在卡佛高中教了12年的 历史与时事
- I was voted teacher of the year three times. A school record.
曾三次获选为年度最佳教师 是本校的最佳纪录
Teaching was all I'd ever wanted to do.
教书始终是我的最爱
Trying to get young people excited about the world.
我想使年轻人对世界充满期待
Trying to prepare them for the tough decisions they'd face as adults.
培养他们用成熟的态度 去面对困难的抉择
That's how I wanted to spend my life.
我想要这样渡过人生
Is this a moral situation or an ethical situation?
这是道德问题还是伦理问题？
What's the difference between morals and ethics anyway? Derek?
道德与伦理有什么不同？ 戴瑞克
Ethics is when you do what society tells you to do.
伦理是由社会告诉你该如何做
- Morals... - You're on the right track.
- 道德是… - 你的方向没错
Can anybody help him out? Michelle.
有谁能帮他补充？蜜雪儿
Morals are like lessons, like the moral of a story.
道德如同是教训 比如说故事中包含的道德
It's what you learn from a story or a fable.
道德是从故事或寓言里学到的
Or a life experience. And ethics?
或是从生活经验里 那么伦理呢？
Ethics is how you use the morals that you learn from the story.
伦理是利用从故事中 学到的道德
We're missing something key here. What are we missing?
我们漏掉了很重要的一点 是什么呢？
- Tracy. - Ethics are rules of conduct...
- 翠茜 - 伦理是…
I'd seen a lot of ambitious students come and go over the years, -
这些年我看过不少 雄心勃勃的学生来来去去
- but Tracy Flick was a special case.
但翠茜・佛立克是个特别例子
People who think I'm an overachiever are just jealous.
认为我过于进取的人 其实是心存妒忌
My mum tells me I'm special.
我妈说我是与众不同的
Looking at what I've accomplished so far, you'd have to agree.
看看我目前为止的表现 你就会同意我的说法
Here I am as Hodel in "Fiddler on the Roof".
我主演“屋顶上的提琴手”
Here I am on KCHS, our student TVstation.
我担任学生电视台的记者
The littering must stop. Tracy Flick reporting.
这场混乱必须停止 翠茜・佛立克报导
The Student Government Association is where I made my biggest mark.
学生自治会是我贡献最多之处
I never missed a single meeting and led nearly every committee.
我从未漏开任何一次会议 几乎主导了所有的委员会
I agree with Ashley. What happened last time was a travesty.
我同意爱希莉的意见 上次简直是场闹剧
It reflected poorly on all of us.
这使我们所有人蒙羞
Now Tracy Flick was poised to win the presidency of the student body.
翠茜一心要赢得学生会主席选举
So far, she was running unopposed.
目前为止还没有其他竞争者
Determined by a culture...
由文化界定…
There's one more thing about Tracy I think you should know.
关于翠茜还有件事值得一提
Her pussy gets so wet, you can't believe it.
她春心荡漾，真难以置信
I don't want to know that.
别告诉我，我不想听这个
A few months earlier, she'd got into some trouble with my best friend.
几个月前她和我的好友 惹出了一点麻烦
Dave Novotny.
他是戴伍・诺沃提尼
Dave came to Carver the year after I did, and we hit it off right away.
戴伍比我晚一年进卡佛教书 我们一见如故
Dave taught because he didn't want to leave high school.
他选择教书是因为 留恋高中生活
Basically he was a good guy. Our wives became best friends, too.
基本上他是个好人 我们的妻子也成为至交
When Dave and Linda's son was born, they asked us to be his godparents.
他们的儿子出生时 认我们做干爹干妈
You probably think that Mr Novotny was abusing one of his students.
或许你以为诺沃提尼老师 利用职权侵犯学生
It wasn't like that.
但事实并非如此
Our relationship was based on mutual respect and admiration.
我们的关系奠基于 彼此的尊敬与钦慕
During my sophomore year it was strictly professional between us.
高二时我们纯粹只有师生关系
It wasn't until junior year that things got kind of serious.
到了高三事情才严重了起来
The yearbook editors were celebrating after a deadline.
纪念册编辑工作完成后 大家一起出去庆功
Dave and I were left alone. We got to talking.
最后只剩下戴伍和我独处 于是我们聊了起来
Not like teacher and student, but like two adults.
我们不以师生的态度谈话 而像是两个成年人
I noticed that you don't have any close friends.
我注意到你没有亲近的朋友
- You seem to be a loner. - I'm just real busy.
- 你似乎是个独行侠 - 不，我只是因为很忙
I know it's not by choice. I just mean that...
我知道不是你选择孤独 我的意思是…
A person like you... It must be hard to find someone to talk to.
像你这样的人一定 很难找到能够谈话的人
What do you mean? What kind of person am I?
什么意思我不懂 我是怎么样的人？
I've been watching you for going on three years now.
我观察了你有三年之久
I think you are one of the most talented, hardworking, attractive -
我认为你是我所见过 最有才华、努力、具吸引力…
- brilliant students... human beings I have ever met.
最聪明的学生 不，最聪明的人
Thank you.
谢谢夸奖
I know sometimes people like you pay a price for their greatness.
我知道像你这样杰出的人 有时必须付出一些代价
And that price is loneliness. Maybe I'm wrong.
这代价就是孤独 或许我说的不对
It just seems to me that you might need a friend.
我只是觉得 你好像需要一个朋友
Growing up without a dad, you might assume I wanted a father figure.
你大概以为长于单亲家庭的我 想要的只是父亲的爱
But that had nothing to do with it. Dave was just so strong.
其实和这件事一点关系也没有 戴伍是如此的强壮
He made me feel safe.
他给了我安全感
It was the first time somebody ever saw the real me.
第一次有人了解真正的我
Okay, get down.
好，趴下
When I think back on my relationship with Mr Novotny, -
每当我回想起 与诺沃提尼老师的关系
- what I miss most is our talks.
最怀念的还是我们的谈话
You did it in your own house?
你在自己家里做？
I know it seems crazy.
我知道听起来很疯狂
What I'm trying to tell you -
我要告诉你的是
- is that Tracy and I are totally, totally... in love.
翠茜和我是完全真心的相爱
- In love? - Yeah. It's serious.
- 相爱？ - 对，我们是认真的
She inspires me. She even wants to read my novel.
她启发了我 她甚至愿意读我的小说
- You haven't written your novel. - I've got it all right here.
- 你又没有写小说 - 小说内容全在我的脑海里
Tracy wants me to write it so she can read it. It's beautiful.
翠茜要我写出来让她看 这多么美妙
Dave, I'm just saying this as your friend...
戴伍，身为朋友我得告诉你
What you're doing is really wrong, and you've got to stop.
你这么做是大错特错 你必须停止
The line you've crossed is immoral and illegal.
你做了不道德的事 而且是犯法的
I don't need a lecture on ethics.
我不需要上伦理课
- I'm talking about morals. - What's the difference?
- 我说的是道德 - 二者有什么不同？
I guess I don't have to tell you how this all turned out.
不用我说你也知道 事情发展到后来的结果
毛伊岛：恋人的天堂 牵着我的手
MAUI IS FOR LOVERS Take my hand...
翠茜，我们去天堂吧 爱你的老师，戴伍
Tracy, let's go to Paradise. Love, your "teacher", Dave.
附注：我现在真的需要你
P.S. I really need you now.
Tracy's mum, she doesn't understand.
翠茜的妈妈不了解
I'd say she doesn't. I have never seen a mother so upset.
我想她的确很不了解 我没看过一个妈妈如此伤心
I know what Tracy told her mother, what her mother told me.
我听过翠茜跟她母亲的说法
I need to hear this from you. I have a legal responsibility here.
现在我需要听你怎么说 这是我的法律职责
Did you cross the line with this girl?
你是否与那女孩 超越了师生的关系？
We're in love.
我们相爱
Your novel? Are you fucking kidding me?
你的小说？ 你他妈的开什么玩笑？
After Dave got fired, Linda kicked him out and filed for divorce.
戴伍被解雇后 琳达把他赶出去并申请离婚
He moved back in with his parents. He's lucky he's not injail.
于是他搬回去跟父母住 没进监狱算他走运了
- Ethics are the basis of... - We'll pick up here next time.
- 伦理是… - 我们下堂课再继续
- Could I retake the last test? - You want to retake it?
- 我可不可以重考？ - 你要重考？
I had to work late the night before.
我前一天晚上去了工作
Now I have more life experience, I feel sorry for Mr McAllister.
如今我多了点人生经验 我替麦考利斯特老师感到悲哀
He's stuck in the same little room, wearing the same clothes, -
他每天困在同样的教室里 穿着同样的衣服
- saying the exact same things year after year-
年复一年说着同样的话
- while his students go to college, move to big cities, -
而他的学生上了大学 离开这里到大城市去
- do great things and make loads of money.
做更棒的工作，赚更多的钱
He's got to be a little jealous.
他一定会有点妒忌
It's like my mum says: "The weak always try to sabotage the strong. "
就像我妈妈常说的 弱者总会试图阻碍强者
It's important to know that I'm an only child.
你必须知道我是个独生女
My mum is really devoted to me. I love her so much.
我妈非常尽力的栽培我 我非常爱她
She wants me to do all the things that she couldn't.
她想要我完成所有 她未能完成的梦
Mum used to be a stewardess and now she works as a paralegal.
她曾当过空姐 现在则是个律师助理
She likes to write letters to successful women -
她喜欢写信给成功的女性
- and ask them what advice do they have for her daughter.
请她们给她的女儿一些忠告
They say you have to hold onto your dreams no matter what.
她们的回答是 无论如何要坚持梦想
You have to work hard and not let anything stand in your way.
你必须努力不让任何东西 挡住你的去路
- Hey, put those back! - Eat me.
- 拿回来 - 谁理你
But winning isn't everything.
但获胜并不是全部
Ethical conduct is more important. Just ask Mr McAllister.
道德行为更加重要 不信你问麦考利斯特老师
Mr McAllister, wait up!
麦考利斯特老师，等一下
Mr McAllister, don't go.
麦考利斯特老师，别走
I got all my signatures. There's 158, way more than I need.
我的连署签名完成了 有158人，远超过我所需要的
- Super. - Here they are.
- 真厉害 - 在这里
I'll take a look at them tomorrow.
我明天早上看
Could you approve them now? I'd like to start campaigning in the morning.
你可以现在批准吗？ 我想明天一早开始竞选活动
- Yeah, those look good to me. - Aren't you supposed to keep them?
- 好，我看没有问题 - 不是应该缴给你吗？
- No, that's fine. - You're supposed to keep them.
- 不用了 - 这应该是给你的
- Right, fine. - Thanks for everything.
- 好吧 - 谢谢你的帮忙
I can't wait to start campaigning.
我等不及开始宣传了
So far there's no competition.
目前为止没有人跟你竞争
Coca-Cola spend more money than anybody on advertising.
可口可乐的广告经费 比其他各厂牌要多
I guess that's how they stay number one.
我想这是他们维持第一的原因
Yeah... Good luck there, Tracy.
祝你好运，翠茜
When I win the presidency, we'll be spending a lot of time together.
我当选学生会主席后 我们会有很多时间相处
I would like that time to be harmonious and productive.
我希望我们的共事 能够和谐且成果丰硕
- Wouldn't you? - Sure.
- 你不希望吗？ - 当然希望
Okay, that's what I thought. I was just checking.
那就好，我想也是 我只是随口问问
- Good luck, Tracy. - Okay.
- 祝你好运，翠茜 - 谢谢
I don't blame Tracy for the trouble with Dave. Dave was an adult.
戴伍惹的麻烦 我并不怪翠茜 因为戴伍是个成年人
She got on my nerves, but I admired Tracy.
虽然我觉得她很烦人 但还是挺钦佩她的
Thank God for Diane. She was my source of love and strength.
感谢老天有黛安 她是我爱与力量的泉源
We'd had bumpy times, but we'd always seen them through.
我们之间也有过不顺利 但总能够渡过
After nine years of marriage, we were closer than ever.
九年的婚姻生活让我们 比以前更亲近
- Anything wrong? - No... just school.
- 哪里不对劲吗？ - 没有，是学校的事
When I win the presidency, we'll be spending a lot of time together.
我当选学生会主席后 我们会有很多时间相处
Lots of time.
很多很多的时间
President and advisor. Harmonious and productive.
学生会主席与辅导员 和谐且成果丰硕
Close and special. You and I.
亲密且特殊，你跟我
- Crystal, what are you doing here? - I've come to see the big game.
- 克莉丝，你来这里做什么？ - 我来看球赛的
- What if coach Henderson walks in? - I'd take care of him.
- 万一韩森教练进来怎么办？ - 我已经收拾他了
- What are you reading? - I'm just reviewing my play book.
- 你在看什么？ - 复习我的笔记
We can practise. You be quarterback. I'll be tight end.
我们来练习吧 你当四分卫，我来做边锋
Coca-Cola is the world's number-one soft drink.
可口可乐是世界第一的饮料厂
Paul.
保罗
I was so mad at God when I broke my leg at Shadow Ridge.
当我度假摔断腿时 我非常怨恨上天
Why?
为什么？
The doctors told me I'd have to quit sports for a couple of years.
医生说我必须暂停运动几年
No first-string quarterback. It was like the end of my life.
无法再当四分卫 我的生命如同到了尽头
When I got back to school everyone was supportive -
回到学校后大家都给我打气
- but I couldn't shake the feeling that now my life had no purpose.
但我仍感到生活没有目标
What did God want from me? Why did I exist?
老天为何要这样对我？ 我为何要活着？
You can search everywhere for answers.
你可以到处寻找答案
Then one day, destiny just walks up and taps you on the shoulder.
突然有一天 命运的手轻拍我的肩膀
I know because it happened to me.
就这么发生在我身上
Paul, can I speak to you?
保罗，可以跟你谈谈吗？
Mr McAllister changed my life.
麦考利斯特老师改变了我的生命
No matter what they say he did, I believe he is a good man.
不管别人说他做了什么 我深信他是个好人
You've been pretty down since your accident.
自从事故发生后你一直很沮丧
I wanted to play football again so bad I could taste it.
我想打橄榄球想得快疯了
- Go on to the playoffs... - I understand disappointment.
- 我还想参加季后赛… - 我了解你的失望
I personally think you have a very bright future ahead of you.
我个人倒觉得 你的前途还是很光明的
- I'm not talking about sports. - What do you mean?
- 我指的不是运动 - 什么意思？
You're a natural leader. You're one of our most popular students.
你是天生的领袖人物 学校最有人缘的学生
And you don't crack under pressure, as we all saw in the Westside game.
你不会因压力而崩溃 看你跟西城比赛的表现就知道
All the kids look up to you. What does that spell?
所有人都很尊敬你 这代表了什么？
Student council president.
学生会主席
Who me? No... I don't know anything about that stuff.
我？不…我不懂那些事
- That's Tracy Flick's thing. - She's a real go-getter.
- 那要翠茜・佛立克才行 - 她的确是很积极
- And she's super nice. - Yeah.
- 而且她的人很好 - 没错
But one person assured of victory undermines democracy.
但当一个人理所当然的获胜 却破坏了民主精神
That would be more like a dictatorship.
就有点像是独裁政治了
- What's your favourite fruit? - Pears.
- 你最喜欢吃什么水果？ - 梨子
- Good, let's say... - Wait!
- 好，这里有… - 等一下
- Apples. - Apples. Fine.
- 苹果好了 - 苹果，好
Let's say all you ever knew were apples.
当你只知道苹果一种水果
You might think apples were good, even if some were rotten.
你觉得苹果很好吃 即使有些是烂苹果
But one day, there's an orange. Now you can make a decision.
但有一天橘子出现了 现在你可以选择
Do you want an apple or an orange? That's democracy.
你可以选择苹果或橘子 这才叫做民主
- I also like bananas. - Exactly. Good.
- 我也喜欢吃香蕉 - 这就对了，说得好
What do you say? Give a little something back.
怎么样？作出一些贡献吧
- How's that? - Just a little higher.
- 这样如何？ - 再高一点点
Eric, you can't put tape on the outside of the poster!
艾立克，不能把胶带 贴在海报正面
You'd better take the whole thing down and redo it.
你最好拆下来重贴一次
保罗・麦兹勒竞选学生会主席
- Who put you up to this? - What do you mean?
- 是谁怂恿你的？ - 哦，嗨，翠茜，你说什么？
You suddenly decided to run for president?
你为何突然间要参选？
I just thought...
我只是想…
I told Mr McAllister that I want to do something for the school.
我跟麦考利斯特老师说 我想为学校做点事
- Mr McAllister asked you to run? - I talked to him.
- 麦考利斯特老师要你参选？ - 我跟他谈过
He thought it was a good idea.
他认为这想法不错
He said that there's all different kinds of fruits.
他说了一些不同的水果
Tracy, you're the best. I just thought...
翠茜，你是最佳人选 我只是想…
Okay, you're on, Mr Popular.
好，一起竞选吧，万人迷先生
Paul Metzler didn't upset me. Nothing was further from the truth.
保罗・麦兹勒并未扰乱我的计划 事实摆在眼前
He was no competition for me.
他根本争不过我
I just had to work a little harder.
我只需要再努力一点
I believe in the voters. This isn't a popularity contest.
我对选民有信心 这又不是最佳人缘选拔
They know this country was built by people who work very hard.
大家都知道这个国家是由 辛苦努力的人建立起来的
Not everyone has everything handed to them.
成功不是人人随手可得的
Not like some rich kids whose fathers own Metzler Cement-
不是每个人都像 麦兹勒水泥厂有钱的小开般
- and give them trucks and throw them big parties.
他只会开车子，开舞会狂欢
They don't ever have to work hard. They just waltz right in -
他根本不需要努力 什么都是唾手可得
- and take what other people have worked hard for all their lives.
并夺走别人终生辛苦的成果
No, it didn't bother me at all.
不，我一点也不会介意
Paul Power.
保罗，力量
Paul for president.
保罗竞选学生会主席
Promise, progress, peanut.
保证，进步，花生
- What? - I told you. I can't.
- 怎么了？ - 我说过我没办法
It just doesn't feel right anymore.
我就是感觉不对劲
But I love you.
可是我爱你
I said, no!
我说不要了
- Tammy, guess what happened today? - Don't you fucking knock?
- 泰咪，你猜今天发生什么事 - 你他妈的不会敲门吗？
- Hi, Lisa. - Get out, Paul.
- 你好，丽莎 - 出去，保罗
- Mr McAllister tells me... - I've got to go.
- 麦考利斯特老师要我… - 我要走了
- You dumb shit! - What did I do?
- 你这个讨厌鬼 - 我哪里犯着你了？
It's not like I'm a lesbian. I'm attracted to the person.
我并不是同性恋 我也会被人吸引
It's just seem to only be attracted to girls.
只是吸引我的人 碰巧都是女人罢了
Lisa, wait.
丽莎，等一下
Stop!
别走
- Where are you going? - I'm not like you.
- 你要去哪里？ - 我不像你
- What do you mean? - I'm not a dyke. We're not in love.
- 什么意思？ - 我不是同性恋，我们没相爱
We're just... experimenting.
我们只是在做实验
How can something that seemed so true turn out to be such a lie?
为何如此真实的感觉 到头来却成为谎言？
Lisa and I were destined to be together.
丽莎和我注定要在一起的
Of all the people on the planet, somehow we found each other.
在地球这么多人里头 我们遇上了
It was like a miracle.
这简直是个奇迹
We had so much fun together. Like the time we ate asparagus -
我们在一起有多么开心 像上次我们拼命吃芦笋
- to see how long it takes before your pee smells funny.
看多久时间能让小便味道改变
It was very scientific. For me it was 11 minutes, for her it was 17.
这非常具科学精神 我是11分钟，她是17分钟
Every day I found a new way to tell Lisa how much I loved her.
每一天我都能用不同方式 告诉丽莎我爱她
If you died, I'd dive into one of my dad's cement trucks -
如果你死了 我就跳进我爸的水泥搅拌车
- and get poured into your tomb.
随水泥倒进你的坟墓
But the closer we got, the more she pulled away.
但我们越亲密，她却越退却
Are you crazy. These are private. These are for us.
你疯了吗？ 这是我们私人的照片
- Other people can see them here. - I don't care.
- 贴在这里会被其他人看到 - 我不在乎
I do!
我在乎
What did I do to make her change?
我做了什么让她改变态度？
What's wrong with me?
我到底有什么问题？
Sometimes when I'm sad, I sit and watch the power station.
有时当我难过时 我会呆坐望着发电厂
They say that if you lie between the main wires, your body evaporates.
有人说假如你躺在主电缆中间 你的身体就会被蒸发掉
You become a gas. I wonder what that would feel like.
你会变成气体 我真想知道那是什么感觉
Lisa decided that she wanted to hurt me.
丽莎决定了要伤害我
And she knew exactly what to do.
而且丝毫不留情
Lisa Flannigan asked me for a ride home and ended up blowing me.
丽莎・佛莱根要我载她回家 结果却替我口交
I've wanted this for so long.
我好久以前就想这么做
Life is so weird. Lisa has a fight with my sister, -
人生真的很奇怪 丽莎跟我妹妹吵了一架
- and the next thing you know she's my girlfriend.
却变成了我的女朋友
She offered to help with the public relations for my campaign.
她自愿替我的竞选活动作公关
We made a great team. It seemed so natural, the two of us together.
我们合作得十分愉快 很自然地就在一起
It was like a miracle.
这简直是个奇迹
My leg was okay and the weather was so nice.
我的腿伤不再困扰我 天气又这么好
After school, we'd go to Lisa's house to fuck and have a hot tub.
放学后我们会去丽莎家 做爱后泡个热水澡
If that's the way they wanted it, that's how it would be.
如果他们要如此逼我 那就只好这样了
But I wasn't going down without a fight.
我是不会不战而败的
泰咪・麦兹勒竞选学生会主席
Tammy, what are you doing?
泰咪，你在做什么？
Stop her. She's not qualified. She's just a sophomore.
阻止她，她资格不符 她只是高二生
Calm down.
别激动
Can we both run? We're brother and sister.
我们两个能同时参选吗？ 我们是兄妹
- It's a conflict of interest. - She got her signatures in.
- 这样会有利益冲突 - 她已经交出连署签名了
These are a bunch of burn-outs. This one is illegible.
这些人全是坏蛋 这个签名根本看不清楚
Tim Cobzer.
提姆・卡哲
- She wants to get back at me. - For what?
- 她是要报复我 - 为什么？
- I mean, at you. - For what?
- 我是说，报复你 - 报复什么？
Tim Cobzer? I've never even heard of him.
提姆・卡哲？没听过这号人物
We'll have the assembly tomorrow.
我们明天会开全校集会
Everyone can make their speeches.
每个人都要发表演说
- You're scaring him. - He likes it... Not that much.
- 你吓着他了 - 他喜欢这样
Around that time, Diane and I were seeing a lot of Linda Novotny.
那段时间里 黛安跟我常去陪琳达
Giving her love and support and helping her in a difficult time.
给她关爱与支持 并帮助她渡过难关
We really wanted to have kids, but there was always a reason to wait.
我们也很想要小孩 但总是时候未到
She had to finish nursing school, I had to get my masters...
黛安得念完护校 我得取得硕士学位
Finally, we decided to go for it.
最后我们决定要生了
Are you going to do it?
你下定决心吗？
For over a year we hadn't had any luck.
努力了一年还是没结果
Come on, do it. Fill me up.
快点，加油，快进来
Come on. Fill me up. Fill me up.
加油，满足我…
Okay.
好了
Good job.
干得好
Jim, can you get this?
吉姆，帮我开好吗？
- Yeah, sure. - Just put it on the table.
- 没问题 - 放在桌上就行
Linda needed a lot of help around the house.
琳达需要人帮忙家里的事
- Here? - No, more this way.
- 这里好吗？ - 不，过去一点
- Here? - Yeah, that's good.
- 这里吗？ - 好，就这里
I'd always liked Linda, but we'd never been alone together.
我一直很喜欢琳达 但我们没有独处过
With Dave out of the picture, I began to see how great she was.
没有戴伍在旁边 我开始发现到琳达很迷人
We got to be kind of buddies. Once I even took her to the mall.
我们逐渐像熟朋友一样 我甚至带她去逛街
- What do you think? - You look great.
- 你觉得如何？ - 你很漂亮
- I can't afford this stuff now. - You've had a hard year.
- 我现在花不起这种钱 - 你这一年过得够辛苦了
You're cooped up all the time with the kid. Live a little.
老是被孩子绑着 偶尔要有自己的生活
- Should we get a room? - Should we get a what?
- 我们该去开个房间吗？ - 开什么？
汽车旅店
That's not funny.
这玩笑没意思
- How did it go? - Fine. We just went to Westfoods.
- 玩得如何？ - 还好，我们去了惠福商场
- Did you guys have fun? - Yeah.
- 开心吗？ - 开心
- I mean, you know... - What?
- 我想… - 怎么了？
Linda's great, but she can be a little bit much sometimes.
琳达人是不错 但有时候不太容易应付
God, just like that. Yeah.
就是这样，对
Fill me up.
满足我
Yeah, fill me up!
对，满足我
God, just like that. Yeah, fill me up.
对，就是这样，满足我
God, just like that. Do it, Jim. Fuck me.
老天，就是这样 快，吉姆，上我
Do it, Jim. Just like that. Fill me up.
就是这样，吉姆，满足我
Just like that. Do it, Mr M. Fuck me.
就是这样，麦老师，上我
Fuck me hard, Mr McAllister. Harder.
用力点，麦考利斯特老师，用力点
Fuck me harder, please.
用力点，求求你
My life was going pretty well-
我的生活还算如意
- until things started going haywire with that damn election.
直到这场可恶的选举混仗开始
I love Carver High and I will be a dedicated vice-president.
我热爱卡佛高中 我会尽责做个学生会副主席
Vote for Jerry Slavin and good government.
请投杰瑞・史拉文 组成好的自治会
Even if I can't really stand up for you, I will.
就算我不能代表你们 我也会努力为大家服务
Thank you.
谢谢你们
Thank you. Jerry is running unopposed for vice-president.
谢谢你，杰瑞 杰瑞是副主席的唯一候选人
We'll move on now to the three presidential candidates.
接下来由学生会主席候选人发表演说
The first, in alphabetical order, is Tracy Flick.
以姓氏排列顺序 第一位是翠茜・佛立克
Henry David Thoreau once wrote:
亨利・大卫・梭罗曾说过
"I cannot make my days longer, so I strive to make them better."
“我无法延长我的生命 因此我努力使它更美好”
At Carver we have an opportunity to make our school days better.
身在卡佛，我们有机会 使学校的生活更美好
During this campaign, I've heard many of your concerns.
在这场选战里 我听到许多同学的心声
Eliza Ramirez says she feels alienated from her own homeroom.
一年级的艾丽莎说 她在班里感到被孤立
Reggie Banks, whose mother works in the cafeteria -
雷吉说 他的母亲在自助餐厅工作
- and can't afford to buy him books.
买不起他的课本
- Eat me. - Eat me raw.
- 无聊 - 无聊透顶
If you can't be adults, and give these candidates some courtesy, -
假如你们不能成熟地 给这些候选人基本的尊重
- you don't deserve to be called adults, but children.
那你们就不配成为大人 而是小孩子
And you'll be treated like children. Let's all listen up.
别怪人家把你们当小孩子看 大家好好听着
I care about Carver and about each and every one of you.
我关心学校 也关心你们所有人
Together we can make a difference.
我们可以同心改造学校
Cast your vote for Tracy Flick, and you won't just be voting for me.
把票投给翠茜・佛立克 不只是把票投给我
You'll be voting for yourself and every other student at Carver.
也是投给你们自己 投给这里的每个学生
Our days might not be any longer but they can sure be better.
也许我们不会在这里待更久 但我们一定可以过得更好
The next candidate is Paul Metzler.
下一位候选人是保罗・麦兹勒
When I broke my leg this year, it made me re-evaluate my life.
今年我摔断腿时 让我对人生有了新的想法
I want to help people and this school.
我想要帮助他人与我们的学校
It's our second home, where we grow as individuals.
这里是我们第二个家 是我们长大成人的地方
I want our school to reach its true potential.
我想要学校真正发挥它的潜力
That's why I'm running for president. I can fight hard.
因此我参选学生会主席 我有坚强的奋斗力
Like when I threw the fourth-quarter pass that beat Westside.
就像我在比赛中奋力一掷 击败了西城队
I won't let you down. We can all score a winning touchdown together.
我不会让你们失望 我们可以共同达阵成功
Vote Paul Metzler for President. Thank you.
请支持保罗・麦兹勒当学生会主席 谢谢
The final presidential candidate is another of the Metzler clan.
最后一位候选人 同样来自麦兹勒家
Tammy Metzler.
泰咪・麦兹勒
People!
同学们安静
Who cares about this stupid election?
谁在乎这愚蠢的选举？
We all know it doesn't matter who gets elected president.
我们都很清楚 不论谁当选学生会主席都没用
Do you really think it's going to change anything?
你们真的以为 会有任何改变吗？
Will it make one single person smarter, happier or nicer?
能让任何一个人更聪明 更快乐或者更亲切吗？
The only person it matters to is the one who gets elected.
唯一有影响的 只有当选的那个人
The same pathetic charade happens every year.
每年都要举行这一场 可悲的游戏
Just so someone gets to put it on their college transcript.
好让某些人把功绩 登录在进大学的成绩单上
Vote for me. I don't even want to go to college.
投我吧，我根本不想进大学
As president, I won't do anything.
假如我当选 我什么事也不做
The only promise I'll make is to dismantle the student government -
我只承诺一件事 就是把学生自治会解散
- so we'll never have another of these stupid assemblies.
这样我们就不用再参加 这种无聊的集会
Tammy! Tammy!
泰咪…
Or don't vote for me. Who cares? Don't vote at all.
不投我也无所谓，谁稀罕？ 干脆大家都别投票了
Close the door.
把门关上
That bitch made a fool out of us. I want her out of this election.
那丫头根本在耍我们 我要让她退出选举
Getting everyone all riled up. She's washed up. Finished.
她煽动了所有人 到此为止，我要她完蛋
We can't stop her just because we don't like her speech.
我们不能因为不满意她的演说 就阻止她参选
Yeah, whatever. But she's a troublemaker. She's on my list.
随你怎么说，她光会惹麻烦 我要把她列在黑名单上
All we need to do is send a message. We should just suspend her.
只要警告她一下就够了 就罚她停学好了
That's it! She's suspended for three days.
就这么办，罚她停学三天
Suspension is like a vacation. Why do they think it's a punishment?
停学就好像放假一样 为什么他们说这是处罚？
If your dog pees on the carpet, do you give him a treat?
假如你的狗在地毯上撒尿 你会给它点心吃吗？
Then you get into trouble for skipping school.
你翘课会惹上麻烦
Hendricks said next time I'd be expelled. It sounded good to me.
亨德里克斯说下次再犯我会被退学 这样才好
净心天主教学校
Hi, Tammy.
泰咪
- What do you want? - I got all your assignments.
- 你要做什么？ - 我帮你拿作业回来
Last time you got suspended you fell so far behind.
上次你被停学课业落后不少
- Thanks a lot, Paul. - Sure, you bet.
- 多谢了，保罗 - 不客气
- Now could you leave me alone? - Yeah.
- 现在你可以走了吗？ - 好
There's just one other thing. All this election stuff...
还有一件事，有关选举…
Everyone's saying it's really weird you're running against me.
大家都觉得很奇怪 你为何要与我对抗
You never really told me why you're doing it.
你也从来没告诉我原因
But that's okay. I respect your privacy.
不过没关系，我尊重你的隐私
I want you to know that no matter who wins, there's no hard feelings.
我只想告诉你，不管谁赢 我们彼此间都不会伤感情
We're still brother and sister, even though you're adopted.
我们还是兄妹，尽管你是养女
I hope you feel the same.
希望你也有同样想法
What happened at the speeches was a travesty.
演说发表简直是一场闹剧
That little bitch isn't going to make a fool out of me.
那个小贱人别想害我出丑
If all those cheering students only knew how hard I worked.
那些欢呼的学生 哪里知道我的辛苦
The nights spent on the yearbook, giving them their stinking memories.
我花了多少时间编辑纪念册 好让他们留下回忆
I had to clean up the group photos.
我的工作包括修补团体照片
A cinch with our new software.
用新软体做起来很简单
People are so ungrateful.
但人总是不懂得感激
谁在乎？我在乎，投翠茜
保罗・麦兹勒-保证酷毙了
The day before the election, things started to get really complicated.
选举前一天 事情开始变得复杂
There's your culprit.
祸首找到了
Linda had asked me to stop by to help with a plumbing problem.
琳达找我顺路帮她修修水管
- Did you know Dave's a bed-wetter? - No, I didn't know that.
- 你知道戴伍尿床吗？ - 我不知道
All his life. He's tried everything.
一辈子改不了 什么方法都试过
- Is that still running clear? - Yeah.
- 水流得还顺畅吗？ - 很好
Better let it run for a while.
最好再让它流一会儿
Wait. Here, this one's clean.
等一下，这是干净的
I guess you'd better get to work. You're going to be late.
你得上班去，不然要迟到了
Thank you, Jim.
谢谢你，吉姆
It just happened. Neither of us planned it.
事情就这么发生了 我们谁也没预期到
But once we started, we knew there was no turning back.
但我们知道一旦开始 就没有回头的余地了
It was a miracle.
这简直是个奇迹
- Take me to that motel. - Now?
- 带我去开房间吧 - 现在？
Come by after school. I'll leave Darryl with a sitter.
学校放学后 我找保姆来带小孩
- 3:25. - Okay, 3:25.
- 三点二十五分 - 好，三点二十五分
What had blossomed between Linda and me was too powerful to deny.
我和琳达之间的情愫 强烈得无法否认
For the first time in years, I felt free and alive.
这么多年来我首次 感觉到奔放和充满生气
- It's not fair. - Who would do something like that?
- 太不公平了 - 谁会做这种事？
It must be a mistake, like a maintenance thing.
或许是维修清洁工弄错了
- Where the hell have you been? - Nowhere.
- 你到哪里去了？ - 哪里也没去
- I don't teach until second period. - I tried you at home.
- 我第二节才有课 - 我打电话去你家了
If Paul loses, we want another election.
如果保罗落选 我们要求重新选举
- Somebody tore down their posters. - They cost us a lot of money.
- 有人撕掉了他们的海报 - 那些海报花了很多钱
- We'll get to the bottom of it. - We still have some extra ones.
- 我们会查清楚的 - 我们还有一些额外的海报
- It was Tammy. - She wouldn't do that.
- 一定是泰咪 - 她不会那么做的
That speech she gave, it was out there.
听她的演说内容 她的确是有嫌疑
We'll get to the bottom of it. You two focus on your studies.
我们会查清楚的 你们两个专心上课
Mr McAllister will handle the whole thing. Right, Jim?
麦考利斯特老师会处理 是吧？吉姆
What's that? Sure, you bet.
你说什么？那当然
Tracy.
翠茜
Tracy, come on in.
翠茜，请进来
Close the door behind you.
把门关上
Have a seat.
坐下
You know why you're here.
你知道为什么被找来
If it's about the posters, I think it's a travesty.
若是关于海报的事 我认为简直是胡闹
A travesty? That's interesting... because I think you did it.
胡闹？这倒有趣了 我认为是你撕的
What?
什么？
Are you accusing me?
你在指控我吗？
We've worked together for three solid years.
枉费我们合作了三年
My own banner was torn down, too.
何况我自己的标语也被撕了
Were you in the Looking Glass office over the weekend?
你上周末是否待在编辑室？
I was. Mr Pecharda let me in.
没错，佩卡老师让我进去的
With my many responsibilities I have to come in on the weekend.
我有职责在身 周末得到学校工作
- I left early, around 6:30. - 6:30?
- 我很早就离开，大概六点半 - 六点半？
How do you know what time the posters were torn down?
你怎么知道海报几点被撕？
I don't, but they were there when I left.
我不知道几点 但我离开时海报还在
I'm giving you helpful information.
我只是提供你调查的线索
We should be trying to figure out who did this.
我们应该合作查出是谁做的
Okay, who do you think did it? Whom should we interrogate?
好，你觉得是谁？ 我们该找谁来问？
It could have been any of the subversive elements at Carver.
可能是学校里一些破坏分子
Like Rick Thieson and those burn-outs.
比如说瑞克・提森 跟那些吸毒的人
What about Tammy Metzler? She's anti this and anti that.
还有泰咪・麦兹勒 她总是反抗这个反抗那个的
You're a very intelligent girl, with a lot of admirable qualities.
你是个很聪明的女孩 有很多令人钦佩的优点
But being smart and doing whatever you need to do to get ahead -
但聪明努力求上进的人
- and stepping on other people...
并不是踩在别人头上前进
There's more to life than that. You're only cheating yourself.
人生还有比求胜更重要的事 你这样只是在欺骗自己
Why are you lecturing me?
你为何对我说教？
This isn't the time or the place to get into it.
我知道此时此地不该提那件事
But for one example, a certain former colleague of mine-
但我要举此为例 某一位我以前的同事
- made a very big mistake.
他也犯了一个大错
I think the lesson here is that we all make mistakes.
我们得到的教训是 任何人都会犯错
We have to learn that our actions can carry serious consequences.
自己任何不慎的行为 都会导致严重的后果
Maybe if certain older, wiser people -
若不是某位年长又聪明的人
- hadn't acted like little babies, then everything would be okay.
行事如同小孩子一样 或许就没有事情会发生
I agree. And certain young and naive people -
我同意，而那位年轻天真的人
- should thank their lucky stars -
应该庆幸自己很幸运
- that the entire school didn't find out about certain indiscretions -
没有被全校的人发觉 她轻率的行为
- that could have ruined their chances to win certain elections.
足以使她的名誉受损 甚至失去当选学生会主席的机会
Certain older people shouldn't be leching after their students.
我认为那些年长的人 不该对他的学生下手
Some can't even get their own wives pregnant.
有的人无法让自己老婆怀孕
And slanderous accusations shouldn't be made to young, naive people -
更不应该对天真的年轻人 做出诽谤性的指控
- whose mothers are paralegal secretaries in successful law firms.
特别是当她的母亲是 知名法律事务所助理
If you want to keep questioning me, I want my attorney present.
如果你要继续质问我 我要求有律师在场
- You wanted to see me? - Wait outside, Tammy.
- 你找我吗？ - 在外头等，泰咪
- Is this about the posters? - Possibly. Wait outside.
- 是关于海报的事吗？ - 可能是，在外头等
Okay, because I know who did it.
好，我知道是谁撕的
So I'll just be outside.
我就在外头等
Don't go anywhere, Tracy. Tammy, come in here.
翠茜，别离开，泰咪你进来
This ought to be good.
最好别乱说话
What do you have to tell me?
你有什么话说？
This is hard for me, but it's important to be honest.
我很难启齿，但做人要诚实
- What is it, Tammy? - I tore down Paul's posters.
- 什么事你说 - 是我撕掉保罗的海报
- I did it. - When did you do it?
- 是我撕的 - 你何时撕的？
Yesterday. Sunday.
昨天，星期天
- How did you get in? - The door was open.
- 你怎么进学校的？ - 门没有关
- Which door? - I don't know. But I did it.
- 哪一扇门 - 我不知道，反正是我撕的
- I don't believe you. - I have proof.
- 我不相信你的话 - 我有证据
Tracy, it looks like today is your lucky day.
翠茜，看来今天是你的幸运日
You're off the hook. Tammy here has confessed.
你没有嫌疑了 泰咪已经承认是她撕的
I told you. You're going to pay for my poster.
我早跟你说了 你要赔偿我的海报
Okay, easy now. Quit while you're ahead.
够了，别激动，别得理不饶人
The rest of the day was unbearable. I kept smelling Linda on my clothes.
接下来的时间真难捱 我不断闻到衣服上琳达的香味
I couldn't wait to get out of there.
巴不得下班时间快到
I wanted everything to be perfect at the motel.
我想将旅馆布置妥当
I decided to give myself some time to prepare during eighth period.
我决定利用第八堂课的时间
Pop-quiz, everybody.
临时小考，同学们
Put your stuff away. If you've done your reading this should be easy.
把东西收起来 有念书就会觉得很简单
I had 48 minutes to arrange it all.
我有48分钟的时间安排一切
If you finish early, sit quietly. I'll be right back.
写完考卷的人安静坐在教室 我马上就回来
Okay everybody, pass them forward. Stephanie, put your pen down.
好了，考卷传上来 斯蒂芬妮，把笔放下
See you on Wednesday. Don't forget to vote tomorrow.
星期三见 明天别忘了要投票
Linda.
琳达
Linda!
Jesus! Oh, fuck!
老天，他妈的
You've reached the Novotny's. We'll call you back real soon.
这里是诺沃提尼家，请留言 我们会尽快回电
Linda, it's me. If you're there, pick up.
琳达，是我 你在的话拿起话筒
It's 4:32. I came by at 3:25, like we said.
现在是四点三十二分 我三点二十五分去找过你
I waited there, but you weren't there.
等了一会儿，但你没出现
I'm at the place we talked about.
我在我们说好的地方
Suite 246.
246号房间
And I'm here. Everything is all set.
我在这里，全都准备好了
So I hope you get here soon. Bye-bye.
希望你快点来，再见
I just don't get it.
我真的不懂
What you have against your mother and me and Paul is beyond me.
我不懂你为何要反抗你妈跟我 还有保罗
Your mother's upset, she's at the end of a rope.
你妈妈很难过 她已经无计可施了
Your behaviour keeps getting crazier and wilder.
你的行为越来越疯狂 越来越野
Who knows what the hell else you're doing!
谁知道你接下来会做什么
I just had a long conversation with Walt Hendricks.
我刚跟亨德里克斯校长谈了好久
I phoned him at home.
还打电话到他家去
He doesn't want you back at Carver. He's fed up with you.
他不要你继续留在卡佛 他受够了你的胡闹
And I don't blame him. What?
我不能怪他，怎么了？
Tammy, your father and I have come to a decision.
泰咪，你爸爸跟我决定了
You're going to Immaculate Heart.
你要转学到净心中学去
Maybe the nuns will be able to straighten you out.
也许修女们能够矫正你的行为
Is that funny?
有什么好笑？
Okay.
好吧
Dear Lord Jesus, I do not often ask you for things -
亲爱的上主 我不常向你提出要求
- but I must insist you help me win the election tomorrow.
但我坚定恳求你 助我赢得明天的选举
I deserve it and Paul Metzler doesn't, as you know.
这是我应得的 不该由保罗・麦兹勒获胜
I realise it was your divine hand that disqualified Tammy Metzler.
我知道是你神圣的手 将泰咪・麦兹勒淘汰
Make sure you put me in office, so that I may carry out your will.
求你让我当上学生会主席 如此我才能执行你的旨意
Amen.
阿们
God, I don't believe in you, but I'm practising for Catholic school.
上主，虽然我不信神 但我得在上天主教学校前练习
What do I want?
我要求什么呢？
I want Lisa to realise what a bitch she is and to apologise to me.
我要丽莎了解她是个大贱人 并且向我道歉
I want Paul to win the election tomorrow, not that cunt Tracy.
我要保罗赢得明天的选举 而不是翠茜那臭婆娘
I also want a pair of expensive leather pants.
我还想要一件昂贵的皮裤
And someday I want to be really good friends with Madonna.
希望将来有一天 我能跟玛丹娜成为好朋友
Dear God, you've given me so many things.
亲爱的天父 你赐与我很多东西
Good health, nice parents, a nice truck -
健康的身体，很好的父母 很棒的车
- and what I'm told is a large penis. I'm grateful.
还有别人都说我的命根子很大 我真的很感激
But I'm worried about Tammy. I can't believe she tore down my posters.
但我很担心泰咪 我仍不信是她撕掉我的海报
But sometimes she gets so angry. Help her be a happier person.
但她有时会愤世嫉俗 请帮助她成为快乐的人
She's so smart and sensitive, and I love her so much.
她很聪明又善解人意 我真的很爱她
I'm nervous about the election tomorrow.
关于明天的选举，我有点紧张
I want to win, but I know it's totally up to you.
我想要获胜 但我知道要由你来决定
You'll decide who the best person is.
你会决定最佳人选 不管是谁我都会接受
Forgive me for my sins, whatever they may be. Amen.
不管我犯了什么罪 请饶恕我的罪
Linda never came home. I waited outside her house for ten hours.
琳达整晚没回家 我在她家外头等了十个钟头
Oh, God.
老天爷
On election day, my mum and I customised 480 cupcakes.
投票那天，我跟我妈 订制了480个小蛋糕
Good morning, Mr M.
早安，麦考利斯特老师
It looks like you could use a cupcake.
看来你需要吃个小蛋糕
What happened to your eye?
你的眼睛怎么了？
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
"Mr McAllister, somebody tore down my poster. It's not fair."
“麦老师，有人撕了我的海报 真不公平”
"Can I have an A? Can I have a recommendation?"
“可以给我甲等吗？ 可以帮我写推荐函吗？”
Fuck them.
去他们的
You've reached the Novotny's. We'll call you back soon.
这里是诺沃提尼家，请留言 我们会尽快回电
Why did you do that? I trusted you completely.
你为什么这么做？ 我完全地相信你
You ruined my life, do you realise that? Do you?
你可知道这样毁了我的生活？
You ruined my life. Is that what you wanted?
你毁了我的生活 这就是你要的吗？
I'm sorry, I'm going nuts here.
对不起，我快要发疯了
I really think we should talk.
我觉得我们需要谈一谈
It's Jim. I love you.
我是吉姆，我爱你
We have an important announcement from our principal, Dr Hendricks.
同学们请注意 亨德里克斯校长有重要事项宣布
Good morning, students.
早安，同学们
It behoves me to inform you of a change in today's election.
我必须通知你们 今天的选举有些变动
Tammy Metzler has been determined ineligible for SGA President.
泰咪・麦兹勒已被取消 学生会主席候选人资格
All other candidates are eligible, but not Tammy Metzler.
除了泰咪・麦兹勒 其他候选人仍具资格
When the time came to vote, I stood in line like everyone else.
投票时刻到来 我和其他人一起排队
- Hi, Tracy. - Tracy Enid Flick.
- 你好，翠茜 - 我是翠茜・佛立克
- Ready, Phil? - Yeah, I'm ready.
- 好了没有？菲尔 - 准备好了
Thanks, Phil.
谢谢，菲尔
Hey, Tracy. Isn't this exciting?
翠茜，很令人兴奋是吧？
- Well, good luck. - Thanks, Paul.
- 祝你好运 - 谢谢，保罗
- You, too. - Thanks.
- 也祝你好运 - 谢谢
It's so weird. Do people always vote for themselves?
我觉得很怪 每个候选人都投自己吗？
Looking at my own name...
看着选票上自己的名字
I don't know... I just felt like it's not right to vote for yourself.
我总觉得投给自己不大对
Okay, Mr M.
投票完成，麦考利斯特老师
- Let's start counting. - Okay, I'll do the first count.
- 开始计票吧 - 好，我先做第一次统计
You can do one of the two independent counts.
然后再由你另行计票一次
Fine. Start with the president, and I'll be right back.
好，从学生会主席开始 我马上就回来
You have the key.
钥匙在你那里
Right.
对了
- Are you okay? - What happened to your eye?
- 你没事吧？ - 你的眼睛怎么了？
I'm fine. It's just a simple, little, everyday bee sting.
我没事 只是被蜜蜂叮了一口
Some people get stung, it's no big deal. Me, I swell up.
有的人被叮一口不会怎样 我却是肿得老大
I'm pressed for time. I have other things going on too, you know?
没时间穷蘑菇了 我还有别的事要做
Yeah, okay. We know.
我们知道
All right, I'll be right back.
好了，我待会就回来
You've reached the Novotny's. We'll call you back real soon.
这里是诺沃提尼家，请留言 我们会尽快回电
It's me again. I'm sorry for all the messages.
又是我 留下这么多留言，很抱歉
If I could just hear your voice. If you'd only acknowledge...
我只想听听你的声音 如果你能了解…
- What do you want, Jim? - You're there.
- 你想怎样？吉姆 - 你在家？
- Yeah, I'm here. - Linda, I love you.
- 对，我在 - 琳达，我爱你
- You know that's not true. - It's the only true thing I know.
- 别这么说，那不是真的 - 我知道这是如假包换的
- We made a mistake. - That was no mistake.
- 我们犯了错 - 我们没有犯错
- You took advantage of me. - I took advantage of you?
- 我寂寞难耐，你占了我便宜 - 我占你便宜？
You hugged me. You kissed me. You're the one...
是你拥抱我吻我，是你…
- Mr M, big day. - Not now, Paul.
- 麦考利斯特老师，今天是大日子 - 现在没心情，保罗
- What have you got? - I'm not supposed to tell.
- 结果如何？ - 我不能说的
- You've got to make your count. - You're kidding, right?
- 你得自行计票一次 - 开什么玩笑
I thought those were the rules. If they've changed...
这不是规定的吗？ 如果规定有更改…
We're not electing the fucking Pope. Just tell me who won.
我们又不是在选教宗 只管告诉我谁赢了
It's a squeaker. I've got Tracy by a vote. Just one vote.
是险胜，翠茜以一票之差获胜
Mr M...
麦考利斯特老师…
Well, okay...
好吧
I guess I'd better do my count.
该我再计票一次了
At the end of my count, I had exactly the same numbers as Larry.
我计票的结果跟赖利一样
256 to 257. Tracy had won the election by a single vote.
256票对257票 翠茜以一票之差获得胜出
I was about to announce my tally when...
正当我要宣布我的计票结果
The sight of Tracy affected me in a way I can't fully explain.
看见翠茜狂喜的样子 给了我难以解释的感觉
Part of it was that she was spying...
除了她偷看的行为
But mostly it was her face.
更令人生厌的是她那张脸
Who knew how far she'd go in life, how much suffering she'd cause?
谁知道她将有多大成就？ 会造成多少人的痛苦？
I had to stop her... Now.
我必须立刻阻止她
Larry... I think we have a problem.
赖利，我想我们有点问题了
253, 245, 255.
253，254，255
I get the same as you, Jim. Paul's our next president.
我得到的数目跟你一样，吉姆 保罗是下一届学生会主席
- It doesn't make sense. - We both get the same figures.
- 这样不对 - 我们两个计票的结果一样
256 for Paul. 255 for Tracy.
保罗256票，翠茜255票
- And 290 disregards. - Mostly Tammy fans.
- 290废票 - 大部分人支持泰咪
It doesn't add up. There were 801 ballots, but 803 people voted.
这与总数不符，有801张选票 但有803人投票
- There must be two votes missing. - Two people pocketed their ballots.
- 一定有两张票遗失 - 有两个人把选票偷藏起来
They were there. I counted 803 votes.
刚刚还在的 我明明数了803票
- People make mistakes. - I didn't.
- 人人都会出错 - 我没弄错
- They were there when you sat down. - I don't like where you're going.
- 你坐下计票前时都还在 - 我不喜欢你的口气
- Every vote was accounted for. - That's enough. End of story.
- 每张票计算得清清楚楚 - 够了，到此为止
I just want to let you know that no matter how this turns out -
我要告诉你，不管结果如何
- you've run a great campaign. Good luck.
你打了一场漂亮的选战 祝你好运
Thanks, Tracy. I'm just glad it's over.
谢谢你，翠茜 我很高兴选战结束了
Let's get started. When the winners are announced, we can all go home.
我们开始宣布结果 宣布完优胜者大家就能回家了
In a contest so well fought it seems unfair to have a winner.
在大家努力的竞争后 很遗憾只能有一位胜利者
Act surprised. Walk slowly to the podium.
故作惊喜状，慢慢走向台前
Be modest. Thank them for this incredible honour.
谦虚地感谢大家 赐与这份荣耀
They're all highly qualified and embody the integrity -
每位候选人都有资格胜利 因为他们展现了
- that we expect from the school leadership.
学生领袖应有的风范
The point of an election is to choose a winner. That you have done.
但选举目的就是要选出优胜者 这是你们所作的决定
We'll begin with the president.
我们从学生会主席开始宣布
This was an extraordinarily close race.
投票结果票数非常的接近
I'd like to announce the next president of Carver High School:
卡佛高中下一届学生会主席是
Paul Metzler.
保罗・麦兹勒
Jeez, you guys, thanks!
老天，谢谢你们
Thanks. I promise to do my best. I'll be a good president.
谢谢，我保证会尽我所能 当个好学生会主席…
Mr M is over there.
麦考利斯特老师在那里
This is so wild. We came here to celebrate my victory.
我真是欣喜若狂 我跟爸妈来这里庆祝胜利
This is great. These are my parents.
这真是太巧了，这是我的父母
- Dick Metzler. - Jim McAllister.
- 我是迪克・麦兹勒 - 吉姆・麦考利斯特
Paul thinks the world of you. He goes on and on.
保罗老把你挂在嘴边 他一直说个不停
You've really helped him out.
你真的帮了他很多
Paul doesn't need any help from me. You should be very proud.
保罗不需要我帮忙 你们应该以他为荣
- We are. - Come over and join us.
- 我们是很高兴 - 何不过来一起用餐？
I'm just finishing up. I've got to get home.
不，我快吃完了 我还得回家
Why don't you guys go sit down.
我看你们先入座
- I want to talk to Mr M. - That sounds great.
- 我有话跟麦考利斯特老师说 - 好
- It was sure nice to meet you. - And thank you.
- 很高兴见到你 - 谢谢你
I have some ideas about what we could do.
我想到一些可以做的事
We could have a carnival with rides, for muscular dystrophy.
我们在学校里装游乐园设施 让同学们锻练肌肉
On Halloween we could have a haunted house, a really good one.
万圣节时弄个很恐怖的鬼屋
Not like those cheesy, bad ones. Super scary.
不是那种简单的鬼屋 要很逼真能吓死人的
For homecoming... Last year's theme was heaven on earth.
至于校庆… 去年的主题是人间仙境
- This year... - We can talk about this later.
- 今年… - 这些我们以后再谈
Right now, I need to finish my pie and go on home.
我现在得把派吃完然后回家
Okay. Sorry. Just one more thing:
好，对不起，还有一件事
Do you think Tracy will be okay? I think she's taking it pretty hard.
你想翠茜不会有事吧？ 她好像受到很大的打击
Don't worry about Tracy. She'll be fine.
别担心翠茜，她不会有事的
Oh, sweetheart...
乖女儿
Baby. Oh, baby...
我的宝贝…
Take one of my pills. You'll feel better.
吃一颗我的药丸 你会感觉舒服点
Here.
来
Come on, baby.
好了，别哭了，宝贝
Lie down. That's a good girl.
躺下来，这才乖
Lie down. Good girl.
躺好，乖女儿
That's it, baby.
好了，宝贝女儿
That's it, honey.
别哭了，乖
Maybe you needed more posters, honey.
可能是因为你的海报不够多
Or if you'd taken my suggestions about your speech...
或者是你的演说稿 没采纳我的意见
I don't know, we'll figure it out.
我也不知道 反正我们会弄清楚的
Diane... I've made a mistake.
黛安，我犯了错…
Did you want the same room?
你要同一个房间吗？
Yeah, okay.
好吧
The next day, I resolved to get my life back on track.
第二天我下定决心 要让生活回到正轨
The way I saw it, getting kicked out of the house was a good thing.
我认为被赶出家门 未尝不是件好事
It was an opportunity. We needed a little time to work things out.
这是个转机 我们需要点时间来解决问题
The election was behind me. The worst was over.
选举一事已被我抛诸脑后 最糟的部分已经结束
What harm had really been done? Nobody was dead.
还能造成什么伤害？ 又没有人死
Jim, Walt wants to see you.
吉姆，校长找你
Okay, thanks.
好，谢谢
You rang?
找我吗？
Mr McAllister, I hope you can help us clear something up.
麦考利斯特老师 这个你作何解释？
- I. - Am.
- 我… - 是
- They. - Are.
-他们… -是
Thank you.
谢谢
Signor Presedente, they want to see you in the office.
学生会主席先生，请到办公室去
Dr Hendricks?
亨德里克斯校长？
Come on in, son. We have something hard we have to tell you.
进来，有个坏消息要告诉你
- Is it about Tammy? - It's about the election.
- 是泰咪的事吗？ - 是关于选举结果
After Paul got the bad news, Walt asked for a word with me.
我们告知保罗坏消息后 校长跟我谈了一下
It was simple. I offered my resignation, and he accepted.
谈话内容很简单 我提出辞呈，他接受辞呈
Very quietly, it was all over for Jim McAllister at Carver High.
吉姆・麦考利斯特在卡佛的教书生涯 就这么无声无息地结束了
Suddenly everyone knew who I was.
突然间我一夕成名
The teacher who tried to crush the dreams of an innocent girl.
成为蓄意破坏 天真女孩梦想的教师
All the good things I'd ever done in my life evaporated.
我过去做的好事 全都消失不见
The wire services picked up on the story.
加上新闻报导的散播
It was the kind of absurd news item that people talk about at work.
成了人们茶余饭后 闲聊的荒谬趣闻
Diane started divorce proceedings. She was completely unforgiving.
黛安开始申请离婚 她完全无法原谅我的外遇
She took almost everything, including the house.
她几乎获得所有的财产 包括房子
I got the car.
我只拿到车子
I realised it was time to get out of Omaha and move on.
我心中明白该离开奥马哈 继续我的生活
Senior year was great. I didn't get to play ball or be president-
高四生活很棒 我没踢球也没当学生会主席
- but I got elected homecoming king.
但被选为校友代表
I got into Nebraska like I wanted.
如愿地进入内布拉斯加大学
At the end of the year, I threw a Mexican party at the cement plant.
毕业前我在水泥厂 开了一个墨西哥舞会
Shit, that was a good party!
出色的派对
The only bad thing was Lisa. She dumped me.
唯一遗憾的是，丽莎把我甩了
One minute we're in love, the next she goes after Randy.
前一分钟我们彼此相爱 转眼间她和我的队友蓝迪在一起
I wonder what would have happened if I'd won the election.
假如我当选学生会主席 不知道会是怎样的景况
Would my whole life be different? Would I never have gone to Yosemite?
我的人生会改变吗？ 我能到约塞米蒂吗？
Or maybe I'd be dead.
说不定我已经死了
Catholic school was great.
天主教学校太棒了
The teachers kind of sucked, and were supposedly strict.
这里的老师很讨厌 也如我预期的严格
But you could get away with murder.
但你也可逍遥法外
The best thing about Immaculate Heart was Jennifer.
读净心中学最棒的是 遇见了詹妮佛
Jennifer and I are soulmates. We're never going to be apart.
詹妮佛跟我是心灵伴侣 我们永远都不要分开
Order! Order!
肃静…
Senior year was very productive.
高四的生活收获很多
I was in the top seventh percentile of my graduating class.
我的毕业成绩名列前茅
I got into Georgetown like I wanted... with scholarships.
如愿拿到奖学金 进入乔治城大学就读
Sometimes I got lonely and I'd think about Dave. I missed our talks.
偶尔我寂寞时会想到戴伍 我怀念我们的谈话
Maybe it could have worked out. I wonder what he's doing now.
也许当时我们可继续在一起 不晓得现在他在干什么？
Maybe he finally finished his novel.
说不定终于完成了他的小说
I had a myriad of accomplishments and a bright future -
我有漂亮的成绩 和耀眼的未来
- but I just didn't feel right.
但我却不觉得高兴
Everybody else seems so happy, signing each other's yearbooks.
其他人都兴高采烈地 拿着毕业纪念册签名
Hardly anybody signed mine.
却很少人签我的
As president, you'd think I'd be surrounded by friends.
人家总以为当了学生会主席 就会有一大堆的朋友
As far as Mr McAllister was concerned, -
至于麦考利斯特老师
- I hardly thought about him at all.
我很少想到他
Nobody had heard from him. It was like he'd never existed.
没有人知道他的消息 似乎从来没有这个人
Tracy Enid Flick.
翠茜・佛立克
At Georgetown, I thought I'd finally be among people more like me.
来到乔治城 我以为终于能找到同类
I was sure that finally I'd make some true friends.
心想自己定能找到 一些知心的朋友
Excuse me, will you please be quiet!
对不起，拜托你们安静点
It wasn't like that at all. They were just spoiled little rich kids.
然而事实却不尽然 只有一些骄纵的富家子弟
I've come to accept that very few people are destined to be special.
我慢慢接受了一个事实 与众不同的人毕竟是极少数
We're solo flyers. It really is like Dave said:
我们是独行侠 就像戴伍所说的
If you're going to be great, you've got to be lonely.
杰出的人总是寂寞的
What happens to a man when he loses everything?
当一个男人失去一切会如何？
Everything he's worked for. Everything he believes in.
失去了所有努力的成果 失去了所有的信念
Driven from his home. Cast out of society.
远离他的家园 被放逐于社会之外
How can he survive? Where can he go?
他要如何生存？ 又能到哪里去呢？
Right this way.
请从这里走
New York City.
就是纽约市
For centuries people have come to New York seeking refuge.
百多年来 人们来到纽约寻求庇护
Now I am one of them. I'd always dreamed of living in New York.
我也成为其中一人 我曾梦想能住在纽约
All that excitement and culture. Life is full of surprises.
处在这个文化冲激的城市 生活充满了惊喜
Once in a while, I even bump into former students.
偶尔我还会碰到以前的学生
My apartment is a little small and the rent is pretty steep, -
我的公寓很小而且租金很贵
- but it's got character, and I'm cosy enough.
但有它的特色 而我也觉很舒适
And it's great not needing a car. I get to read on the subway.
不需开车也挺棒的 我可以在搭地铁时看书
Some days, I even walk to work.
有时候我还走路去上班
The job market is tight, but after hunting around a while -
这里的工作不好找 不过在我四处搜寻后
- I landed a job in the education department at the museum.
终于在博物馆的教育部门 谋得一职
I'm teaching again.
我又开始教学了
When a school brings its students to the museum on a field trip, -
若有学校带学生来博物馆 校外教学时
- there's a staff of trained educators to greet them.
会由受过训练的教育馆员 来接待他们
I've started seeing someone new. Jillian.
我也开始与姬莉安约会
She works at the museum, too.
她也在博物馆工作
She's really different from Diane. I've never met anyone like her.
她跟黛安很不一样 我从未遇过她这种女性
She just ended a relationship, too, so we're trying to take it slow.
她也刚结束一段感情 所以我们都想慢慢来
You might ask if I ever saw Tracy Flick again. I did, just once.
你可能想知道我是否有 再见到翠茜，见过一次
I was down in Washington for a museum educators' conference.
我到华盛顿去参加 博物馆员会议时
After an inspiring morning on the Mall, -
在商场渡过充实的早上后
- I was on my way to the Holocaust Museum, when...
在前往纳粹屠杀博物馆的路上
I'll never know if she saw me. Probably not.
我不知她是否看见了我 或许没有吧
But just then, all the bad memories, everything I'd wanted to tell her, -
但所有不愉快的过往 和我一直想骂她的话
- it all came flooding back.
在那一刻猛然涌上心头
I wanted to run over there and tell her I knew about the posters.
我很想跑过去告诉她 我知道是她撕了海报
And how she'd cheated her way into winning that election.
她是靠作弊才赢得那次的选举
But instead, I just stood there.
然而我却只是站在那里
I realised I wasn't angry at her anymore. I just felt sorry for her.
我发觉自己不再对她气愤 而是为她感到悲哀
When I think about my new life, and what her life must be like...
想到我拥有的新生活 而她的生活是多么悲惨
She probably still gets up early to pursue her pathetic little dreams.
或许她仍一大早起床 去追逐那些可笑的梦想
Where is she really trying to get to anyway?
她真以为自己有多行？
What is she doing in that limo? Who the fuck does she think she is?
她坐着大轿车干什么？ 她以为自己是谁？
Hey, you!
你干什么？
You asshole!
混帐东西
That's all ancient history now. I've got a whole new life.
那些都是陈年旧事了 我已经有全新的生活
That's what's great about America. You can always start over.
这就是身在美国的好处 你永远有机会从头开始
Would that make this an igneous or a sedimentary rock?
这是火成岩还是沉积岩？
What's the difference between igneous and sedimentary?
火成岩与沉积岩有什么不同？
Anybody?
还有谁会？